<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jonas Bolldén</title>
    <link>https://www.bldn.se/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Jonas Bolldén</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2020 10:59:01 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.bldn.se/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Another chapter begins</title>
      <link>https://www.bldn.se/2020/08/13/another-chapter-begins/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2020 10:59:01 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.bldn.se/2020/08/13/another-chapter-begins/</guid>
      <description>In the great book of work life the current chapter is coming to a close. On August 1st 2017 I began my position as Team Manager (“Consultant Manager”) at the Luleå office of Sogeti. In the beginning I were responsible for 34 IT-consultants. This grew to as high as 38 at one point.
During these three years I’ve learned a lot about myself and my leadership, about people and business, about technology and solutions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Power of the Tribe</title>
      <link>https://www.bldn.se/2019/07/30/power-of-the-tribe/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2019 10:31:09 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.bldn.se/2019/07/30/power-of-the-tribe/</guid>
      <description>I joined the tribe!
This July I had the utmost priviliege to be part of SoLEAD16; the 16thclass of Sogeti Leadership Academy. 26 collegues from across the world gathered under the safe wings of our facilitators Dian Lens and Mandy Sol. For three intense days we shared, cared, told and networked at the Capgemini Campus Serge Kampf Les Fontaines, a good one hour car ride north of Paris, France.
Below is the description of this awesome programme:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finding Modern Agile</title>
      <link>https://www.bldn.se/2018/05/25/finding-modern-agile/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 May 2018 16:35:14 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.bldn.se/2018/05/25/finding-modern-agile/</guid>
      <description>Being the longtime, die hard Scrum advocate that I know I am, it’s with somewhat mixed emotions I’ve just now discovered Modern Agile.
 Modern Agile is ultra-light, the opposite of mainstream Agile, which is drowning in a bloated tangle of enterprise tools, scaling frameworks and questionable certificates that yield more bureaucracy than results.1
 The four principles, values, cornerstones, or whatever you want to call them, are elegant distillations of my beloved Scrum and certainly of all of the agile frameworks and toolboxes:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Have fun at work</title>
      <link>https://www.bldn.se/2017/06/04/have-fun-at-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2017 14:35:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.bldn.se/2017/06/04/have-fun-at-work/</guid>
      <description>We often hear that it&amp;rsquo;s important to enjoy our work, but this post is about an alternative phrase. “Have fun at work” shifts focus from work as action to work as environment.
Over a course of maybe four years I&amp;rsquo;ve come to shift my position on what&amp;rsquo;s important when it comes to work. In the beginning my position was that the work tasks had to be what motivated me while working, but now I’ve come to realise that the context of where the work tasks are performed has precedence.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Next step, new challenge</title>
      <link>https://www.bldn.se/2017/05/30/next-step-new-challenge/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 May 2017 12:28:40 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.bldn.se/2017/05/30/next-step-new-challenge/</guid>
      <description>I’ve been given this amazing opportunity that would be outright stupid to turn down, and I’m usually not stupid. I’ll be taking on the position as team manager at the consultancy Sogeti here in Luleå. I’m looking forward to return to my old firm where I spent five years and eight months at the office of Linköping.
Through this I will of course be putting myself to the test. As always, I’m humbled before the task(s) at hand, but I believe I can do some good together with my new colleagues.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let Scrum masters be Scrum masters</title>
      <link>https://www.bldn.se/2017/04/27/let-scrum-masters-be-scrum-masters/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2017 19:00:16 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.bldn.se/2017/04/27/let-scrum-masters-be-scrum-masters/</guid>
      <description>The last couple of years I&amp;rsquo;ve seen an increase in job offerings for Scrum masters here in Sweden. The title of these adverts more often than not include the text “Scrum master”. This shows that the market is adapting more and more to the need for agile methodologies, and Scrum in particular. And this is of course great news, but…
Lately I&amp;rsquo;ve started to read these adverts more thoroughly and have found that none of them are for a position as a fulltime Scrum master.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More effective meetings</title>
      <link>https://www.bldn.se/2017/01/19/more-effective-meetings/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2017 09:45:42 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.bldn.se/2017/01/19/more-effective-meetings/</guid>
      <description>In a constant search for improvement, here is a suggestion on what to consider when it comes to meetings.
Basic principle Respect should always serve as the basic principle, and there is no difference when it comes to meetings.
Meet or not to meet? The first question to ask is always &amp;ldquo;Why a meeting?&amp;rdquo;. The answer creates the basis for the meeting&amp;rsquo;s purpose. E.g., is it some sort of one-way communication it may in many cases be enough to send the information via e-mail instead of setting up a meeting where perhaps only a few people are actively involved.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Experience as argument</title>
      <link>https://www.bldn.se/2017/01/18/experience-as-argument/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2017 16:52:10 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.bldn.se/2017/01/18/experience-as-argument/</guid>
      <description>This post is as much a suggestion to you as it is a reminder to myself.
Experiences are important parts of life; it&amp;rsquo;s something we accumulate more or less throughout our lives. Wikipedia reads:
 Experience is the knowledge or mastery of an event or subject gained through involvement in or exposure to it.1
 However, there is another side to this which the following quote tries to illustrate:
 Never argue with an idiot.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Retrospective and Feedback</title>
      <link>https://www.bldn.se/2016/09/30/retrospective-and-feedback/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2016 16:39:29 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.bldn.se/2016/09/30/retrospective-and-feedback/</guid>
      <description>Straight out of the Scrum guide1:
 The Sprint Retrospective is an opportunity for the Scrum Team to inspect itself and create a plan for improvements to be enacted during the next Sprint.
 and
 By the end of the Sprint Retrospective, the Scrum Team should have identified improvements that it will implement in the next Sprint. Implementing these improvements in the next Sprint is the adaptation to the inspection of the Scrum Team itself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let&#39;s meet, on time!</title>
      <link>https://www.bldn.se/2016/09/24/lets-meet-on-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Sep 2016 07:47:14 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.bldn.se/2016/09/24/lets-meet-on-time/</guid>
      <description>The other day I read the great &amp;ldquo;Two Simple Secrets to Starting Every Meeting on Time&amp;rdquo;. Here @sabinanawaz presents two simple rules on &amp;ldquo;how to save time in meetings and be even more productive&amp;rdquo;:
 Meet for 45 minutes instead of an hour. Start meetings at quarter past the hour.  One could say I&amp;rsquo;ve used the first rule for quite some time, but the meetings were set for 50 minutes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scrum values added to the Scrum guide</title>
      <link>https://www.bldn.se/2016/09/12/scrum-values-added-to-the-scrum-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2016 10:37:33 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.bldn.se/2016/09/12/scrum-values-added-to-the-scrum-guide/</guid>
      <description>In July of 2016 the Scrum guide was updated, thus adding the Scrum values mentioned in the great &amp;ldquo;Agile Development with Scrum&amp;rdquo;. The text reads as follows, with me highlighting the five values:
 When the values of commitment, courage, focus, opennessand respectare embodied and lived by the Scrum Team, the Scrum pillars of transparency, inspection, and adaptation come to life and build trust for everyone. The Scrum Team members learn and explore those values as they work with the Scrum events, roles and artifacts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://www.bldn.se/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Sep 2016 10:52:22 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.bldn.se/about/</guid>
      <description>At its core, this site is a blog. Wikipedia defines this as:
 A blog (a truncation of the expression weblog) is a discussion or informational site published on the World Wide Web and consisting of discrete entries (&amp;ldquo;posts&amp;rdquo;) typically displayed in reverse chronological order (the most recent post appears first). ~ Wikipedia
 This means that the site is by me, Jonas Bolldén, and it holds my thoughts and ideas mainly related to different aspects of IT and software development.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Breaking news: Change of scenery</title>
      <link>https://www.bldn.se/2016/05/19/breaking-news-change-of-scenery/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 May 2016 16:12:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.bldn.se/2016/05/19/breaking-news-change-of-scenery/</guid>
      <description>Both me and my wife have been recruited by Luleå University of Technology. As of September 1st she will begin her work as a Educational Developer with special responsibility for Information and Communication Technology (ICT) at University Pedagogy Centre (HPC), and I as a Project Manager at IT Services (ITS) with responsibilities for the public and portal websites. We are both very grateful for these opportunities and look forward to start a new and exiting chapter in our lives.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#34;CSPs Changing the World&#34;</title>
      <link>https://www.bldn.se/2016/05/06/csps-changing-the-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2016 13:36:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.bldn.se/2016/05/06/csps-changing-the-world/</guid>
      <description>Should Scrum Alliance contact me for a spot on their page &amp;ldquo;CSPs Changing the World&amp;rdquo; the following could be the text they might publish.
Meet Jonas Bolldén CSP® Jonas Bolldén lives in Linköping, Sweden, and is a consultant for Sogeti Sverige AB.
For you, what is the main difference between where you began as a CSM®, CSPO®, or CSD® and becoming a CSP?
That would be confidence; added confidence is the main difference.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The better Scrum poster</title>
      <link>https://www.bldn.se/2016/05/04/the-better-scrum-poster/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2016 17:56:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.bldn.se/2016/05/04/the-better-scrum-poster/</guid>
      <description>I rarely use projectors or computers while facilitating meetings. There are occasions where those kind of tools are perfect, but my main reason for not using them is my style of facilitation; I&amp;rsquo;m much more comfortable with a whiteboard (or a flip chart) and a set of coloured markers.
However, there is one specific exception to this, and that&amp;rsquo;s when the meeting is related to the subject of Scrum. On these occasions I keep one image ready to be presented.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ghost on Nginx with Let&#39;s Encrypt certificate</title>
      <link>https://www.bldn.se/2016/04/24/ghost-on-nginx-with-lets-encrypt-certificate/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Apr 2016 17:18:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.bldn.se/2016/04/24/ghost-on-nginx-with-lets-encrypt-certificate/</guid>
      <description>I wanted to secure my Nginx web server with the use of this new free service Let&amp;rsquo;s Encrypt and the people over at DigitalOcean are always busy making sure there&amp;rsquo;s a lot of great tutorials for the rest of us.
Following the instructions in &amp;ldquo;How To Secure Nginx with Let&amp;rsquo;s Encrypt on Ubuntu 14.04&amp;rdquo; has nos given me HTTPS-capabilities.
This blog is, at the time of writing, running on Ghost, an awesome node.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scrum - finding a baseline</title>
      <link>https://www.bldn.se/2016/04/07/scrum-finding-a-baseline/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2016 13:17:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.bldn.se/2016/04/07/scrum-finding-a-baseline/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday I had the privilege to run a workshop with nine engaged participants, all from the same company and all in some way working with Scrum. Most of the participants knew each other from before and the gathering was held at a conference centre away from the office.
The purpose of the gathering was to create a boilerplate of interested persons that can help their company become more fluent in Scrum.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to conduct a workshop</title>
      <link>https://www.bldn.se/2016/03/11/how-to-conduct-a-workshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Mar 2016 17:04:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.bldn.se/2016/03/11/how-to-conduct-a-workshop/</guid>
      <description>I was invited to hold a short introduction on how to conduct workshops. The audience was comprised of about 20 persons, in different ways connected to the practice of UX (User experience). I had one hour at my disposal, and I&amp;rsquo;ve tried to summarise my thoughts on the subject in this post.
Definition A workshop1 is
 a meeting at which a group of people engage in intensive discussion and activity on a particular subject or project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Perspectives: Why Scrum projects fail</title>
      <link>https://www.bldn.se/2016/02/24/perspectives-why-scrum-projects-fail/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2016 06:55:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.bldn.se/2016/02/24/perspectives-why-scrum-projects-fail/</guid>
      <description>There are three main reasons to why Scrum projects fail. On this I will elaborate in this post.
The most obvious reason is of course that the Scrum framework isn&amp;rsquo;t used properly. There are a plethora of articles, books, courses, gatherings, communities, forums, user groups, consultants, and so on, that can help you understand and implement Scrum as it is intended.
However, the other two main reasons are not as obvious and both are connected to perspective.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Me becoming a Certified Scrum Professional</title>
      <link>https://www.bldn.se/2016/02/19/me-becoming-a-certified-scrum-professional/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2016 09:03:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.bldn.se/2016/02/19/me-becoming-a-certified-scrum-professional/</guid>
      <description>Last December (2015) I got my application for Certified Scrum Professional (CSP) approved by Scrum Alliance. On their website they define this as:
 Certified Scrum Professionals have demonstrated experience, documented training, and proven knowledge in the art of Scrum.
 As explained on this page the process of becoming a CSP is quite rigorous.
My application The soft argument(s) The following is the text I submitted 2015-11-24 to argue my knowledge of Scrum and its impact on me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upgrading Ghost</title>
      <link>https://www.bldn.se/2015/12/03/upgrading-ghost/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2015 08:44:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.bldn.se/2015/12/03/upgrading-ghost/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m not comfortable with the upgrade procedure that&amp;rsquo;s suggested on the support page &amp;ldquo;How to Upgrade Ghost&amp;rdquo;. The following post describes my way of upgrading.
By monitoring the GitHub page you&amp;rsquo;ll see when there&amp;rsquo;s a new version released.
Current setup I&amp;rsquo;m running my Ghost blog on a Linux Droplet at DigitalOcean and use a somewhat different procedure to upgrade my Ghost blog to the latest release. The setup is on Nginx much like described in this post with the use of Supervisor to keep Ghost as a service.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SGPRG2015 - My first gathering</title>
      <link>https://www.bldn.se/2015/11/19/sgprg2015-my-first-gathering/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Nov 2015 14:10:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.bldn.se/2015/11/19/sgprg2015-my-first-gathering/</guid>
      <description>This is a short and simple report of my first Global Scrum Gathering that took place at the Hilton Prague between the 16th and 18th of November 2015.
The two cent summary: I would go to the next one if possibility arises, I would even consider being a speaker.
The program with session descriptions as a PDF can be accessed through SGPRG SessionDescriptions Aug20.pdf and the slides from the different presenters, facilitators, and what not, can be found online here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Case of sprint planning meeting</title>
      <link>https://www.bldn.se/2015/11/16/case-of-sprint-planning-meeting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Nov 2015 22:40:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.bldn.se/2015/11/16/case-of-sprint-planning-meeting/</guid>
      <description>Some time ago I sat in on a development team&amp;rsquo;s sprint planning meeting for iteration 17 of a new product at a large organisation. The team was a normal sized team with 5-7 developers, a Scrum Master and a Product Owner. I&amp;rsquo;d say the developers are experienced but not senior, the person assigned as Scrum Master has been in IT for many years, and the Product Owner, who is from another department, has also worked for some time at the organisation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scrum, so far - product backlog</title>
      <link>https://www.bldn.se/2015/08/12/scrum-so-far-product-backlog/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2015 15:03:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.bldn.se/2015/08/12/scrum-so-far-product-backlog/</guid>
      <description>A product backlog is a prioritised list of items yet to be added to the product. An item is something that someone wants to be part of the product. The product backlog is responsibility of the Product Owner.
In my opinion the easiest way to administrate the product backlog is as a shared spreadsheet document (Google Docs, Office 365, Dropbox, network share, etc.). The main reason is the ease of use, e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scrum, so far - a set of articles</title>
      <link>https://www.bldn.se/2015/08/07/scrum-so-far-a-set-of-articles/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2015 14:35:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.bldn.se/2015/08/07/scrum-so-far-a-set-of-articles/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been involved with Scrum since early 2008. It all started with an information day held by HiQ in Stockholm, Sweden. In a series of articles I will elaborate on different subjects of the Scrum framework, on what I&amp;rsquo;ve learned so far. List of subjects is at the end of this article.
You, the reader, should have some idea of what Scrum is and hopefully you&amp;rsquo;ve been involved with some Scrum yourself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical grounds for RESTful APIs</title>
      <link>https://www.bldn.se/2014/06/10/theoretical-grounds-for-restful-apis/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2014 16:35:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.bldn.se/2014/06/10/theoretical-grounds-for-restful-apis/</guid>
      <description>There is a lot said and written about REST and being RESTful, and in this post I give my two cents when it comes to what theoretical grounds I use when creating RESTful APIs.
In the year 2000 Roy Thomas Fielding published his dissertation Architectural Styles and the Design of Network-based Software Architectures. The last sentence of the abstract&amp;rsquo;s third paragraph reads:
 I then introduce the Representational State Transfer (REST) architectural style and describe how REST has been used to guide the design and development of the architecture for the modern Web.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>All simple with GetSimple</title>
      <link>https://www.bldn.se/2014/02/14/all-simple-with-getsimple/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2014 13:54:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.bldn.se/2014/02/14/all-simple-with-getsimple/</guid>
      <description>In moving my personal site from a Rackspace Cloud Server to a Raspberry Pi I was looking for a lightweight substitution for the earlier used CMS concrete5. I found GetSimple CMS:
 GetSimple is an XML based, stand-a-alone, fully independant and lite Content Management System. To go along with its best-in-class user interface, we have loaded it with features that every website needs, but with nothing it doesn&amp;rsquo;t. GetSimple is truly the simplest way to manage a small-business website.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rackspace Cloud Backup on Arch 2013.6</title>
      <link>https://www.bldn.se/2013/08/26/rackspace-cloud-backup-on-arch-2013-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2013 12:02:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.bldn.se/2013/08/26/rackspace-cloud-backup-on-arch-2013-6/</guid>
      <description>Since the applications, data, and services on my Rackspace (this) server is becoming more and more important I decided to look into Rackspace&amp;rsquo;s Cloud Backup service. However, I ran into trouble during the setup of the service, and this article tries to describe how it was solved.
I followed their guide to Install the Agent. There is an AUR for the driveclient that could be used, but at the moment I&amp;rsquo;m not that keen on using AUR&amp;rsquo;s, and at the time of writing the version in the AUR is also a bit old.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updating Arch 2013.2 on Rackspace</title>
      <link>https://www.bldn.se/2013/06/07/updating-arch-2013-2-on-rackspace/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2013 07:51:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.bldn.se/2013/06/07/updating-arch-2013-2-on-rackspace/</guid>
      <description>With June 3rd came an update for Arch Linux that gave me some server trouble I couldn&amp;rsquo;t recover from. I had to start my Rackspace server in Rescue Mode to get my data back (files and databases). On the upside I found that Rackspace had upgraded the image to build from, now it&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Arch 2013.2&amp;rdquo;. So I rebuilt the server from that image. This article describes how I upgraded the server and created a new image that could be used for creating new servers on Rackspace.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reinstalling all packages in Arch Linux</title>
      <link>https://www.bldn.se/2013/04/17/reinstalling-all-packages-in-arch-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2013 00:53:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.bldn.se/2013/04/17/reinstalling-all-packages-in-arch-linux/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been a Gentoo user for years and just recently switched to Arch Linux as my distribution of choice. Since Gentoo is a source based distribution I found that it usually was a good idea to reinstall the packages on the base system.
Even though Arch Linux is not a source distribution I personally still like to reinstall all packages just to make sure all is well. By combining some of the tips and tricks listed at the wiki page Pacman Tips you could achieve this.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CodeIgniter introduces $_SERVER[&#39;CI_ENV&#39;]</title>
      <link>https://www.bldn.se/2013/02/23/codeigniter-introduces-_serverci_env/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Feb 2013 19:10:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.bldn.se/2013/02/23/codeigniter-introduces-_serverci_env/</guid>
      <description>On the 3rd of March last year (2012) &amp;lsquo;roberto-butti&amp;rsquo; suggested using a server environment variable to control the value of CodeIgniter&amp;rsquo;s ENVIRONMENT. The full discussion on the issue can be found at GitHub. And in June Phil Sturgeon added logic for this in index.php (see commit).
By using Apache&amp;rsquo;s SetEnvIf-directive in .htaccess it is possible to set conditional server environment variables.
Let&amp;rsquo;s say you have three different server environments; production, testing, development and they all resides on different hostnames; www.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sorting in SQL</title>
      <link>https://www.bldn.se/2012/12/04/sorting-in-sql/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Dec 2012 15:42:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.bldn.se/2012/12/04/sorting-in-sql/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s not completely uncommon to come across databases set to use collations and/or code pages where the ORDER BY clause won&amp;rsquo;t sort as expected; e.g. Åke might be sorted before Carl.
A quick fix to this is to use either the CAST()- or the CONVERT()-function on the text field you wish to sort by. I tend to use CAST() since it&amp;rsquo;s ANSI standard. However, CONVERT() works with all data types, while CAST() don&amp;rsquo;t.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SQL Buddy, the unmaintained alternative</title>
      <link>https://www.bldn.se/2012/11/14/sql-buddy-the-unmaintained-alternative/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Nov 2012 17:46:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.bldn.se/2012/11/14/sql-buddy-the-unmaintained-alternative/</guid>
      <description>If you, as I, think that phpMyAdmin is a useful tool but unnecessarily complex in regards of installation and user experience, then SQL Buddy might be the alternative for you.
SQL Buddy is a web based administration tool for MySQL written in PHP. This tool is simple to use, yet potent enough to meet all the basic and some of the advanced needs one might have when working with MySQL databases.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PHP 5.4.x packs a built-in web server</title>
      <link>https://www.bldn.se/2012/09/02/php-5-4-x-packs-a-built-in-web-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Sep 2012 21:42:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.bldn.se/2012/09/02/php-5-4-x-packs-a-built-in-web-server/</guid>
      <description>New in PHP from version 5.4.x is a built-in web server perfect for use during development. By issuing the following command in a terminal you will be able to serve the content in ~/public_html over port 8080:
$ php -S 0.0.0.0:8080 -t ~/public_html  A more comprehensive article on the subject can be found at the php.net-site: Built-in web server.
On a side note you should remember that the built-in server is PHP specific, i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use latest CodeIgniter in your project</title>
      <link>https://www.bldn.se/2012/08/12/use-latest-codeigniter-in-your-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2012 15:56:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.bldn.se/2012/08/12/use-latest-codeigniter-in-your-project/</guid>
      <description>The development branch of the PHP framework CodeIgniter resides on GitHub and can be cloned by anyone. This article will outline a suggestion on how to set up a project that is continuously based on the latest version available in the repository.
I&amp;rsquo;ll explain how to create, develop and maintain your project through the following steps:
 Prepare your project area Fetch latest CodeIgniter Copy directories and files Start development of your project Update CodeIgniter  Prepare your project area Create a directory that will hold your project and CodeIgniter:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>