<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>scrum on Jonas Bolldén</title>
    <link>https://www.bldn.se/tags/scrum/</link>
    <description>Recent content in scrum on Jonas Bolldén</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2017 19:00:16 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.bldn.se/tags/scrum/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Let Scrum masters be Scrum masters</title>
      <link>https://www.bldn.se/2017/04/27/let-scrum-masters-be-scrum-masters/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2017 19:00:16 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.bldn.se/2017/04/27/let-scrum-masters-be-scrum-masters/</guid>
      <description>The last couple of years I&amp;rsquo;ve seen an increase in job offerings for Scrum masters here in Sweden. The title of these adverts more often than not include the text “Scrum master”. This shows that the market is adapting more and more to the need for agile methodologies, and Scrum in particular. And this is of course great news, but…
Lately I&amp;rsquo;ve started to read these adverts more thoroughly and have found that none of them are for a position as a fulltime Scrum master.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Retrospective and Feedback</title>
      <link>https://www.bldn.se/2016/09/30/retrospective-and-feedback/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2016 16:39:29 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.bldn.se/2016/09/30/retrospective-and-feedback/</guid>
      <description>Straight out of the Scrum guide1:
 The Sprint Retrospective is an opportunity for the Scrum Team to inspect itself and create a plan for improvements to be enacted during the next Sprint.
 and
 By the end of the Sprint Retrospective, the Scrum Team should have identified improvements that it will implement in the next Sprint. Implementing these improvements in the next Sprint is the adaptation to the inspection of the Scrum Team itself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scrum values added to the Scrum guide</title>
      <link>https://www.bldn.se/2016/09/12/scrum-values-added-to-the-scrum-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2016 10:37:33 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.bldn.se/2016/09/12/scrum-values-added-to-the-scrum-guide/</guid>
      <description>In July of 2016 the Scrum guide was updated, thus adding the Scrum values mentioned in the great &amp;ldquo;Agile Development with Scrum&amp;rdquo;. The text reads as follows, with me highlighting the five values:
 When the values of commitment, courage, focus, opennessand respectare embodied and lived by the Scrum Team, the Scrum pillars of transparency, inspection, and adaptation come to life and build trust for everyone. The Scrum Team members learn and explore those values as they work with the Scrum events, roles and artifacts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#34;CSPs Changing the World&#34;</title>
      <link>https://www.bldn.se/2016/05/06/csps-changing-the-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2016 13:36:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.bldn.se/2016/05/06/csps-changing-the-world/</guid>
      <description>Should Scrum Alliance contact me for a spot on their page &amp;ldquo;CSPs Changing the World&amp;rdquo; the following could be the text they might publish.
Meet Jonas Bolldén CSP® Jonas Bolldén lives in Linköping, Sweden, and is a consultant for Sogeti Sverige AB.
For you, what is the main difference between where you began as a CSM®, CSPO®, or CSD® and becoming a CSP?
That would be confidence; added confidence is the main difference.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The better Scrum poster</title>
      <link>https://www.bldn.se/2016/05/04/the-better-scrum-poster/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2016 17:56:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.bldn.se/2016/05/04/the-better-scrum-poster/</guid>
      <description>I rarely use projectors or computers while facilitating meetings. There are occasions where those kind of tools are perfect, but my main reason for not using them is my style of facilitation; I&amp;rsquo;m much more comfortable with a whiteboard (or a flip chart) and a set of coloured markers.
However, there is one specific exception to this, and that&amp;rsquo;s when the meeting is related to the subject of Scrum. On these occasions I keep one image ready to be presented.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scrum - finding a baseline</title>
      <link>https://www.bldn.se/2016/04/07/scrum-finding-a-baseline/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2016 13:17:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.bldn.se/2016/04/07/scrum-finding-a-baseline/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday I had the privilege to run a workshop with nine engaged participants, all from the same company and all in some way working with Scrum. Most of the participants knew each other from before and the gathering was held at a conference centre away from the office.
The purpose of the gathering was to create a boilerplate of interested persons that can help their company become more fluent in Scrum.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Perspectives: Why Scrum projects fail</title>
      <link>https://www.bldn.se/2016/02/24/perspectives-why-scrum-projects-fail/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2016 06:55:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.bldn.se/2016/02/24/perspectives-why-scrum-projects-fail/</guid>
      <description>There are three main reasons to why Scrum projects fail. On this I will elaborate in this post.
The most obvious reason is of course that the Scrum framework isn&amp;rsquo;t used properly. There are a plethora of articles, books, courses, gatherings, communities, forums, user groups, consultants, and so on, that can help you understand and implement Scrum as it is intended.
However, the other two main reasons are not as obvious and both are connected to perspective.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Me becoming a Certified Scrum Professional</title>
      <link>https://www.bldn.se/2016/02/19/me-becoming-a-certified-scrum-professional/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2016 09:03:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.bldn.se/2016/02/19/me-becoming-a-certified-scrum-professional/</guid>
      <description>Last December (2015) I got my application for Certified Scrum Professional (CSP) approved by Scrum Alliance. On their website they define this as:
 Certified Scrum Professionals have demonstrated experience, documented training, and proven knowledge in the art of Scrum.
 As explained on this page the process of becoming a CSP is quite rigorous.
My application The soft argument(s) The following is the text I submitted 2015-11-24 to argue my knowledge of Scrum and its impact on me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SGPRG2015 - My first gathering</title>
      <link>https://www.bldn.se/2015/11/19/sgprg2015-my-first-gathering/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Nov 2015 14:10:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.bldn.se/2015/11/19/sgprg2015-my-first-gathering/</guid>
      <description>This is a short and simple report of my first Global Scrum Gathering that took place at the Hilton Prague between the 16th and 18th of November 2015.
The two cent summary: I would go to the next one if possibility arises, I would even consider being a speaker.
The program with session descriptions as a PDF can be accessed through SGPRG SessionDescriptions Aug20.pdf and the slides from the different presenters, facilitators, and what not, can be found online here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Case of sprint planning meeting</title>
      <link>https://www.bldn.se/2015/11/16/case-of-sprint-planning-meeting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Nov 2015 22:40:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.bldn.se/2015/11/16/case-of-sprint-planning-meeting/</guid>
      <description>Some time ago I sat in on a development team&amp;rsquo;s sprint planning meeting for iteration 17 of a new product at a large organisation. The team was a normal sized team with 5-7 developers, a Scrum Master and a Product Owner. I&amp;rsquo;d say the developers are experienced but not senior, the person assigned as Scrum Master has been in IT for many years, and the Product Owner, who is from another department, has also worked for some time at the organisation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scrum, so far - product backlog</title>
      <link>https://www.bldn.se/2015/08/12/scrum-so-far-product-backlog/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2015 15:03:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.bldn.se/2015/08/12/scrum-so-far-product-backlog/</guid>
      <description>A product backlog is a prioritised list of items yet to be added to the product. An item is something that someone wants to be part of the product. The product backlog is responsibility of the Product Owner.
In my opinion the easiest way to administrate the product backlog is as a shared spreadsheet document (Google Docs, Office 365, Dropbox, network share, etc.). The main reason is the ease of use, e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scrum, so far - a set of articles</title>
      <link>https://www.bldn.se/2015/08/07/scrum-so-far-a-set-of-articles/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2015 14:35:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.bldn.se/2015/08/07/scrum-so-far-a-set-of-articles/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been involved with Scrum since early 2008. It all started with an information day held by HiQ in Stockholm, Sweden. In a series of articles I will elaborate on different subjects of the Scrum framework, on what I&amp;rsquo;ve learned so far. List of subjects is at the end of this article.
You, the reader, should have some idea of what Scrum is and hopefully you&amp;rsquo;ve been involved with some Scrum yourself.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>